<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Develop on Yangyang Li's Geek Logs</title><link>https://yangyangli.top/tags/develop/</link><description>Recent content in Develop on Yangyang Li's Geek Logs</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>Yangyang Li - [Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 International License](https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/).</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 Sep 2022 23:22:31 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://yangyangli.top/tags/develop/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Bioinformatics Toolbox Aka Boss</title><link>https://yangyangli.top/posts/009-new-tool-bioinformatics-toolbox-aka-boss/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Sep 2022 23:22:31 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://yangyangli.top/posts/009-new-tool-bioinformatics-toolbox-aka-boss/</guid><description>BOSS is a bioinformatics toolbox, which will contain efficient tools. It is written in modern C++ and is tested exhaustively. It is designed to be easy to use and time-efficient. BOSS is a free software and is distributed under the terms of the GNU General Public License V3.
Currently, BOSS contains the following tools:
boss-fqsp : A fast tool for splitting fastq files into paired files. boss-squeue: Summary Status of Jobs in HPC Queues It is now evolving and will be updated frequently.</description></item><item><title>Guide for building Cpp Development in Bioinformatics</title><link>https://yangyangli.top/posts/003-guide-build-cpp-development-env-with-htslib/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2022 23:17:30 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://yangyangli.top/posts/003-guide-build-cpp-development-env-with-htslib/</guid><description>1. Config Compile Environment I am preparing to develop a tool using C++ in the Linux and macOS environments. Usually, I do not have root rights to download dependencies for C++ using apt-get install -y denpendencies directly in Ubuntu. However, I usually feel frustrated when the dependency chain is complicated. That means I need to download and compile every library I use. This may cost you one night or even one week.</description></item><item><title>A Python Toolbox - Pybox</title><link>https://yangyangli.top/posts/001-a-wonderful-library-you-must-not-know/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Dec 2021 00:03:50 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://yangyangli.top/posts/001-a-wonderful-library-you-must-not-know/</guid><description>1. Introduction Many people have been asking for a toolbox of useful commands for their everyday tasks. I also want to build a toolbox for my own use, and I want to make it as easy as possible to use. Hence, I decided to build this project, which may be a valuable tool for other people as well. I will add more commands to this toolbox once I find them useful in the future.</description></item></channel></rss>