<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Algorithm on Yangyang Li's Geek Logs</title><link>https://cauliyang.github.io/tags/algorithm/</link><description>Recent content in Algorithm on Yangyang Li's Geek Logs</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>Yangyang Li - [Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 International License](https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/).</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2022 13:07:28 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cauliyang.github.io/tags/algorithm/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Bioinformatics Algorithm Library aka BINARY</title><link>https://cauliyang.github.io/posts/011-bioinformatics-algorithm-library/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2022 13:07:28 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://cauliyang.github.io/posts/011-bioinformatics-algorithm-library/</guid><description>The library is a collection of algorithms and data structures that are designed for modern C++ bioinformatics applications. You can use the library in your own projects or as a part of a larger project.
The library will include efficient data structure and algorithm implemented by Modern C++.
The design philosophy of the library:
Embrace C++20 standard Supports modern C++ features Support concurrency and thread safety Priority is given to safety and clean design Hard to use wrongly Testing extensively Python bindings The current project is developing and evolving, and changes will be made to the library as time goes on.</description></item><item><title>Nei Saitou Neighbor Joining</title><link>https://cauliyang.github.io/posts/008-nei-saitou-neighbor-joining/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2019 11:15:00 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://cauliyang.github.io/posts/008-nei-saitou-neighbor-joining/</guid><description>1. Background Before diving into code, the description of NJ algorithm can be found in , where first column indicates parent node, and second column is its children node, the last column is the value of edge.
2. Neighbor Joining Algorithm The Neighbor-joining Algorithm Given a distance matrix d compute an uprooted tree topology complete with edge lengths that tries to preserve the additive property: $d_{i,m} + d_{j,m} − d_{i,j} = 2d_{k,m}$ where $k$ is the k-th node on both routes from $i$ and $j$ to $m$.</description></item></channel></rss>